# Bilal Zahory

703-282-7267 | bzahory@gmail.com | https://github.com/bzahory | https://bzah.bz

## SUMMARY

Web3 frontend-oriented full-stack engineer with 9 years of development experience (5 years professional).

Enabled millions in profits by creating responsive, optimized dApps UIs with React, Tailwind, and TypeScript; ensured product scalability by implementing pragmatic, well-tested data flows to and through these dApps UIs using Node, Redux, ethers, and Jest.

#### Experience

Full Stack Engineer | Same Stack + Node/Express, Solidity, Vite, SCSS, Go MetaMask

August 2023 – Present Fully Remote

- Achieved a \$15,000,000 run rate for MetaMask Bridges with 2 other developers (see: Dune)
- Doubled mobile revenue share by implementing and optimizing a conversion flow from MetaMask Mobile with performance optimizations, auto-scrolling, and native-like web components
- Enabled 2000+ targeted survey responses by creating a custom hook to add functionality to the existing survey provider
- Reduced overhead by \$40k+/month by executing a multi-phased migration from an external provider to an in-house offering

Frontend Engineer | React, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, Ethers, Tailwind, MixPanel May 2022 - August 2023 MetaMaskFully Remote

- Developed the MetaMask Bridges user interface (UI) using React (TypeScript) and Redux to enable the seamless transfer of tokens across 9 EVM Compatible Blockchains
- Drove \$550,000,000+ in volume and \$4,250,000+ in fee revenue (see: Dune) since launching in November 2022
- Led optimization initiatives by incorporating navigational lazy loading, JS thread yielding and lint-enforced tree shaking, resulting in a 25% decrease in FCP time and eradication of all 22 long tasks in a testing flow

Frontend Engineer / Founder | React Native, JavaScript, Expo

March 2021 – April 2022

Buzz Crypto

Sterling, VA

- Created a group crypto trading app UI using React Native
- Implemented a lightweight touch-to-data mapping function which cut down touch latency for a feature by 90%

#### Computer Science Teacher | HTML, CSS, JS

August 2019 - March 2021

Coder Kids Inc.

McLean, VA

• Taught 100+ classes on the basics of web development to groups of 15+ K-8 students

## Projects

Puzzle App w/ Auth | React, TypeScript, Next, Prisma, Tailwind, next-auth, bcrypt

- Engineered a fully-featured puzzle app with password-based web authentication and profiles
- Filled in knowledge gaps from primarily working in web3 (e.g., traditional authentication methods, relational databases, managing profiles, handling passwords)

School Website | HTML, CSS, JS

• Developed a mobile-friendly single-paged website that won first place out of 50 teams at the Academies of Loudoun

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript, Solidity, HTML, CSS, JS, Go

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Jest, SCSS

Libraries: Redux, Ethers, Express, Tailwind, Wagmi

#### EDUCATION

### Northern Virginia Community College

Associate of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Academies of Loudoun (Magnet Program)

High School Diploma (Computer Science Track)

Sterling, VA

December 2020

Leesburg, VA

June 2020